Suppose you're left to decide what degree of polynomial to fit to a data set.
Imaginemos que te gustaría decidir
So that what features to include that gives you a learning algorithm.
qué grado de polinomio ajustar
Or suppose you'd like to choose the regularization parameter longer for
a un conjunto de datos,
learning algorithm.
o qué funciones incluir para utilizar tu algoritmo de aprendizaje.
How do you do that?
O supongamos que quieres elegir
This account model selection process.
el parámetro de regularización «lambda» para el algoritmo de aprendizaje.
Browsers, and in our discussion of how to do this, we'll talk about not just how to
¿Cómo lo harías?
split your data into the train and test sets, but how to switch data into what we
Estos se llaman problemas de selección de modelo.
discover is called the train, validation, and test sets.
En nuestra discusión de
We'll see in this video just what these things are, and
cómo resolverlos, hablaremos
how to use them to do model selection.
no sólo sobre cómo
We've already seen a lot of times the problem of overfitting,
dividir los datos en los conjuntos de
in which just because a learning algorithm fits a training set well,
prueba y aprendizaje, sino también sobre cómo
that doesn't mean it's a good hypothesis.
dividir los datos en lo
More generally, this is why the training set's error is not a good predictor for
que llamaremos
how well the hypothesis will do on new example.
conjuntos de validación y de prueba.
Concretely, if you fit some set of parameters.
En este video veremos qué son
Theta0, theta1, theta2, and so on, to your training set.
estos conjuntos y cómo
Then the fact that your hypothesis does well on the training set.
podemos utilizarlos para seleccionar un modelo.
Well, this doesn't mean much in terms of predicting how well your hypothesis will
Ya hemos visto en muchas
generalize to new examples not seen in the training set.
ocasiones el problema del sobreajuste,
And a more general principle is that once your
que nos dice que no sólo porque el
parameter is what fit to some set of data.
algoritmo de aprendizaje se ajusta bien un
Maybe the training set, maybe something else.
conjunto de entrenamiento, la hipótesis será buena.
Then the error of your hypothesis as measured on that same data set,
De manera más general, esta es
such as the training error,
la razón por la cual el error del conjunto de entrenamiento no
that's unlikely to be a good estimate of your actual generalization error.
es una buena variable predictiva para saber
That is how well the hypothesis will generalize to new examples.
qué tan efectiva será la hipótesis con nuevos ejemplos.
Now let's consider the model selection problem.
Específicamente, si aplicas un
Let's say you're trying to choose what degree polynomial to fit to data.
conjunto de parámetros, «theta» 0,
So, should you choose a linear function, a quadratic function, a cubic function?
«theta» 1, «theta» 2,
All the way up to a 10th-order polynomial.
y sucesivamente, a tu
So it's as if there's one extra parameter in this algorithm,
conjunto de entrenamiento, el hecho de
which I'm going to denote d, which is, what degree of polynomial.
que la hipótesis sea efectiva
Do you want to pick.
en el conjunto de entrenamiento no
So it's as if, in addition to the theta parameters, it's as if
significa mucho en cuanto a la
there's one more parameter, d, that you're trying to determine using your data set.
predicción de qué tan bien
So, the first option is d equals one, if you fit a linear function.
se generalizará la hipótesis
We can choose d equals two, d equals three, all the way up to d equals 10.
con ejemplos que no se han visto antes
So, we'd like to fit this extra sort of parameter which I'm denoting by d.
en el conjunto de entrenamiento.
And concretely let's say that you want to choose a model,
El principio más general es que,
that is choose a degree of polynomial, choose one of these 10 models.
una vez que los parámetros fueron ajustados
And fit that model and also get some estimate of how well your
a un conjunto de datos, ya sea el
fitted hypothesis was generalize to new examples.
conjunto de entrenamiento o cualquier otro,
Here's one thing you could do.
el error de la hipótesis,
What you could, first take your first model and minimize the training error.
como se midió en el mismo
And this would give you some parameter vector theta.
conjunto de datos, tal como el
And you could then take your second model, the quadratic function, and
error de entrenamiento, tal vez no resulta
fit that to your training set and this will give you some other.
en un estimado adecuado
Parameter vector theta.
del error de generalización real; es decir,
In order to distinguish between these different parameter vectors, I'm going
qué tan bien se generalizará la
to use a superscript one superscript two there where theta superscript one
hipótesis con los nuevos ejemplos.
just means the parameters I get by fitting this model to my training data.
Ahora consideremos el problema de selección de modelo.
And theta superscript two just means the parameters I
Digamos que intentas elegir qué
get by fitting this quadratic function to my training data and so on.
grado de polinomio ajustar a los datos.
By fitting a cubic model I get parenthesis three up to, well, say theta 10.
¿Debes elegir una función lineal, una
And one thing we ccould do is that take these parameters and look at test error.
función cuadrática o una cúbica?
So I can compute on my test set J test of one,
¿Qué función, hasta un polinomio del 10 orden, debes elegir?
J test of theta two, and so on.
Entonces, hay un parámetro adicional en
J test of theta three, and so on.
este algoritmo, que denotaré con
So I'm going to take each of my hypotheses with the corresponding parameters and
una “d”, que indica
just measure the performance of on the test set.
qué grado de polinomio quieres utilizar.
Now, one thing I could do then is, in order to select one of these models,
De manera que
I could then see which model has the lowest test set error.
además de los
And let's just say for
parámetros theta,
this example that I ended up choosing the fifth order polynomial.
hay un parámetro más (d)
So, this seems reasonable so far.
que intentamos determinar utilizando el conjunto de datos.
But now let's say I want to take my fifth hypothesis, this, this,
La primera opción es “d”
fifth order model, and let's say I want to ask, how well does this model generalize?
igual a 1, que corresponde a la función
One thing I could do is look at how well my fifth order
lineal. Podemos elegir
polynomial hypothesis had done on my test set.
“d” igual a 2, “d” igual a 3,
But the problem is this will not be a fair estimate of how well my
y, hasta “d”
hypothesis generalizes.
igual a 10. Queremos, entonces,
And the reason is what we've done is we've fit this extra parameter d,
ajustar este parámetro adicional,
that is this degree of polynomial.
que denotaremos como parámetro “d”.
And what fits that parameter d, using the test set, namely,
Y digamos que quieres
we chose the value of d that gave us the best possible performance on the test set.
elegir un
And so, the performance of my parameter vector theta5, on the test set,
modelo, es decir, elegir
that's likely to be an overly optimistic estimate of generalization error.
un grado de polinomio o uno de estos
Right, so, that because I had fit this parameter d to my test set is no longer
diez modelos, y ajustarlo
fair to evaluate my hypothesis on this test set, because I fit my parameters
para obtener un estimado de
to this test set, I've chose the degree d of polynomial using the test set.
qué tan bien se generalizará la
And so my hypothesis is likely to do better on
hipótesis ajustada a
this test set than it would on new examples that it hasn't seen before, and
nuevos ejemplos. Aquí hay algo que podrías
that's which is, which is what I really care about.
hacer: podrías
So just to reiterate, on the previous slide, we saw that if we fit some set of
tomar tu primer modelo y
parameters, you know, say theta0, theta1, and so on, to some training set,
minimizar el error de entrenamiento
then the performance of the fitted model on the training set is not predictive of
para que arroje el
how well the hypothesis will generalize to new examples.
parámetro vector «theta».
Is because these parameters were fit to the training set,
Después puedes tomar tu segundo modelo,
so they're likely to do well on the training set,
la función cuadrática, y
even if the parameters don't do well on other examples.
ajustarla al conjunto de entrenamiento.
And, in the procedure I just described on this line, we just did the same thing.
Esto te dará otros parámetros vector «theta».
And specifically, what we did was, we fit this parameter d to the test set.
Para distinguir entre los
And by having fit the parameter to the test set, this means that
diferentes parámetros de vector, utilizaré
the performance of the hypothesis on that test set may not be a fair estimate of how
el superíndice 1 y el superíndice 2
well the hypothesis is, is likely to do on examples we haven't seen before.
donde «theta» superíndice
To address this problem, in a model selection setting,
1 se refiere al parámetro que
if we want to evaluate a hypothesis, this is what we usually do instead.
obtendré ajustando
Given the data set, instead of just splitting into a training test set,
este modelo a mis datos de entrenamiento y
what we're going to do is then split it into three pieces.
«theta» superíndice 2 se refiere
And the first piece is going to be called the training set as usual.
al parámetro que obtendré al ajustar la
So let me call this first part the training set.
función cuadrática a mis datos de entrenamiento.
And the second piece of this data, I'm going to call the cross validation set.
Cuando ajuste el modelo cúbico obtendré el parámetro «theta» 3, y así
[SOUND] Cross validation.
sucesivamente hasta «theta» 10.
And the cross validation, as V-D.
Otra cosa que podemos
Sometimes it's also called the validation set instead of cross validation set.
hacer es tomar estos
And then the loss can be to call the usual test set.
parámetros y buscar el error del conjunto de prueba.
And the pretty, pretty typical ratio at which to split these things will be
Puedo calcular en mi
to send 60% of your data's, your training set,
conjunto de prueba “j prueba” de
maybe 20% to your cross validation set, and 20% to your test set.
«theta» 1, “j prueba” de
And these numbers can vary a little bit but this integration be pretty typical.
«theta» 2,
And so our training sets will now be only maybe 60% of the data, and our
“j prueba” de «theta» 3,
cross-validation set, or our validation set, will have some number of examples.
y así sucesivamente.
I'm going to denote that m subscript cv.
Luego tomaré
So that's the number of cross-validation examples.
cada una de mis hipótesis
Following our early notational convention I'm going to use xi cv comma y i cv,
con sus parámetros correspondientes y mediré
to denote the i cross validation example.
su desempeño en el conjunto de prueba.
And finally we also have a test set over here with our
Para seleccionar uno de estos modelos,
m subscript test being the number of test examples.
una de las cosas que
So, now that we've defined the training validation or
puedo hacer es
cross validation and test sets.
ver que modelo
We can also define the training error, cross validation error, and test error.
tiene el error del conjunto de prueba más
So here's my training error, and
bajo. Digamos,
I'm just writing this as J subscript train of theta.
que para este ejemplo
This is pretty much the same things.
elegimos el polinomio de quinto orden.
These are the same thing as the J of theta that I've been writing so
Esto parece ser razonable hasta el momento,
far, this is just a training set error you know, as measuring a training set and then
pero qué pasa si quiero
J subscript cv my cross validation error, this is pretty much what you'd expect,
tomar mi hipótesis ajustada; es decir, el
just like the training error you've set measure it on a cross validation data set,
modelo del quinto orden,
and here's my test set error same as before.
y preguntarme qué tan bien se generaliza este modelo.
So when faced with a model selection problem like this, what we're going to
Para responder esto
do is, instead of using the test set to select the model, we're instead
puedo analizar qué tan bien
going to use the validation set, or the cross validation set, to select the model.
se desempeñó la hipótesis del polinomio de quinto orden en mi conjunto de prueba.
Concretely, we're going to first take our first hypothesis, take this first model,
El problema de esto es que
and say, minimize the cross function, and
no será un estimado
this would give me some parameter vector theta for the new model.
justo de qué tan
And, as before, I'm going to put a superscript 1,
bien se generaliza mi hipótesis.
just to denote that this is the parameter for the new model.
La razón es que, lo que hemos hecho
We do the same thing for the quadratic model.
es ajustar
Get some parameter vector theta two.
este parámetro adicional “d”, que
Get some para, parameter vector theta three, and so
es el grado del polinomio,
on, down to theta ten for the polynomial.
utilizando el
And what I'm going to do is, instead of testing these hypotheses on the test set,
conjunto de prueba “d”.
I'm instead going to test them on the cross validation set.
En otras palabras, elegimos el valor
And measure J subscript cv,
de d que nos dio
to see how well each of these hypotheses do on my cross validation set.
el mejor desempeño posible
And then I'm going to pick the hypothesis with the lowest cross validation error.
en el conjunto de prueba.
So for this example, let's say for the sake of argument,
El desempeño de mi
that it was my 4th order polynomial, that had the lowest cross validation error.
parámetro vector «theta» cinco
So in that case I'm going to pick this fourth order polynomial model.
del conjunto de prueba probablemente dará
And finally, what this means is that that parameter d,
un estimado muy optimista
remember d was the degree of polynomial, right?
del error de generalización.
So d equals two, d equals three, all the way up to d equals 10.
¿Sí? Debido a que he ajustado
What we've done is we'll fit that parameter d and we'll say d equals four.
este parámetro “d” a mi
And we did so using the cross-validation set.
conjunto de prueba,
And so this degree of polynomial, so the parameter, is no longer fit to the test
ya no es justo
set, and so we've not saved away the test set, and we can use the test set to
evaluar mi hipótesis en este conjunto de prueba.
measure, or to estimate the generalization error of the model that was selected.
Esto es porque he ajustado mis parámetros al conjunto de prueba y
By the of them.
he elegido el grado “d” del polinomio
So, that was model selection and how you can take your data,
utilizando el conjunto de prueba. De modo
split it into a training, validation, and test set.
nuestra hipótesis, probablemente,
And use your cross validation data to select the model and
será más efectiva
evaluate it on the test set.
en este conjunto de prueba que
One final note, I should say that in.
en nuevos ejemplos
The machine learning, as of this practice today, there aren't many
que no se han visto antes. Es por esto que estamos aquí.
people that will do that early thing that I talked about, and said that, you know,
Solo por recapitular,
it isn't such a good idea, of selecting your model using this test set.
en la diapositiva anterior
And then using the same test set to report the error as though
vimos que si ajustamos
selecting your degree of polynomial on the test set, and then reporting the error on
un grupo de parámetros, digamos «theta»
the test set as though that were a good estimate of generalization error.
0, «theta» 1, etc., a
That sort of practice is unfortunately many, many people do do it.
un conjunto de entrenamiento, entonces
If you have a massive, massive test that is maybe not a terrible thing to do,
el desempeño del modelo ajustado en
but many practitioners,
el conjunto de entrenamiento no
most practitioners that machine learnimg tend to advise against that.
predirá qué tan bien
And it's considered better practice to have separate train validation and
se generaliza la hipótesis en
test sets.
nuevos ejemplos, porque estos
I just warned you to sometimes people to do, you know, use the same data for
parámetros se ajustarían al conjunto de entrenamiento.
the purpose of the validation set, and for the purpose of the test set.
Y probablemente se desempeñarán bien en
You need a training set and a test set, and that's good,
este conjunto de entrenamiento, aún si
that's practice, though you will see some people do it.
los parámetros no se desempeñan bien en otros ejemplos.
But, if possible, I would recommend against doing that yourself.
Y en el procedimiento que acabo de describir